<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>齐林的博客</title>
    <link>https://larryqi.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on 齐林的博客</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 18 Jul 2018 14:00:00 +0800</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://larryqi.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title> What is the difference between AI, Machine Learning, NLP, and Deep Learning?</title>
      <link>https://larryqi.github.io/posts/what-is-the-difference-between-ai-machine-learning-nlp-and-deep-learning/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Jul 2018 14:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://larryqi.github.io/posts/what-is-the-difference-between-ai-machine-learning-nlp-and-deep-learning/</guid>
      <description>Quora
Artificial Intelligence (A.I.) A field of study with the goal of creating machines that exhibit intelligence.
Machine Learning (ML) A sub-field of AI, whose focus is to use data to train computer algorithms to perform tasks that typically cannot be done (or very difficult to accomplish) through hard wiring the logic into a program, because no one is quite sure what the rules are. Recognizing objects in images is one such task where the rules are unclear.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>《富爸爸穷爸爸》读后感（一）</title>
      <link>https://larryqi.github.io/posts/%E5%AF%8C%E7%88%B8%E7%88%B8%E7%A9%B7%E7%88%B8%E7%88%B8%E8%AF%BB%E5%90%8E%E6%84%9F1/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Mar 2018 22:36:44 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://larryqi.github.io/posts/%E5%AF%8C%E7%88%B8%E7%88%B8%E7%A9%B7%E7%88%B8%E7%88%B8%E8%AF%BB%E5%90%8E%E6%84%9F1/</guid>
      <description> 序 &amp;emsp;&amp;emsp;《富爸爸,穷爸爸》一书是一本十分畅销也十分“另类”的书,畅销书作家罗伯特·清崎用自己的亲身经历讲述了富人如何教育孩子有关金钱的问题,而这些看似常识的关于金钱的观念和知识却是穷人和中产阶级家庭所没有的.可以说作者在此书中一语道破了“富人的秘密”。
第一章 富人不为钱工作 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to talk about the economy</title>
      <link>https://larryqi.github.io/posts/how-to-talk-about-the-economy/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Apr 2016 13:36:44 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://larryqi.github.io/posts/how-to-talk-about-the-economy/</guid>
      <description>How to talk about the economy
 GDP -&amp;gt; gross domestic product
  This is the total value, the total monetary value of goods and services within a country.  fiscal
  anything to do with money, anything to do with financial matters, especially when we’re talking about taxes. fiscal year : it’s the beginning of its tax year to the end of its tax year.  quarter</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to improve your listening</title>
      <link>https://larryqi.github.io/posts/my-first-post/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Mar 2016 13:36:44 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://larryqi.github.io/posts/my-first-post/</guid>
      <description>How to imporove your listening in English
 Watch movies or T.V.
 first time use your native language subtitle then change it to English subtitle Watch without subtitle  Listen to music
 not to learn grammar lyric  Go out
 go out to the country where people communicate in English. listen to people talking make friends with foreigner   </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title> A Gentle Guide to Machine Learning</title>
      <link>https://larryqi.github.io/posts/a-gentle-guide-to-machine-learning/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Feb 2015 13:36:44 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://larryqi.github.io/posts/a-gentle-guide-to-machine-learning/</guid>
      <description>Original address: A Gentle Guide to Machine Learning
Machine Learning is a subfield within Artificial Intelligence that builds algorithms that allow computers to learn to perform tasks from data instead of being explicitly programmed.
Got it? We can make machines learn to do things! The first time I heard that, it blew my mind. That means that we can program computers to learn things by themselves!
The ability of learning is one of the most important aspects of intelligence.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>https://larryqi.github.io/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2015 13:36:44 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://larryqi.github.io/about/</guid>
      <description>Hi, my name is Lin Qi ,and I graduated from Shanghai Jiao Tong University, with a Master’s degree of Engineering in 2018. My current location is Shanghai, in China.  On the web and with friends, I am also known as &#34;larryqi&#34;, which has been my nickname since a long time ago.  You should probably also know that I do not have a sleep schedule, which means that I am usually awake whenever there is work to do.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>